<ModMetaData>
	<name>GeneticRim b18</name>
	<author>Sarg</author>
	<targetVersion>0.18.1722</targetVersion>
	<description>Extract DNA from animals and hybridize them to create new, exotic species!

&lt;size=24&gt;Features&lt;/size&gt;

- Hybridization: Extract genes from Bears, Chickens, Boomalopes, Muffalos, Wolves, Rodents, Reptiles, Insectoids and Thrumbos, and create hybrids of these species. Some combinations can go both ways, so for example a bearalope is different from a boombear, and you will get one at random. A total of 49 new creatures for you to play with. Some very useful, others... less so.

- Hybrid implants: By extracting humanoid genes, you can mix them with animal genes and create several hybrid implants to improve your colonists.

- Alpha Creatures: With the Animal Enrichment research, you can turn regular animals into Alphas, more evolved versions of the base creature. A total of 9 new creatures for you to play with.

&lt;size=24&gt;Issues&lt;/size&gt;
Some of the biggest animals might flicker. This is to be expected, since a few of them are bigger than Thrumbos!
The Boombeetle is a ranged creature, and the code for it is beta, so expect erratic behaviour (specially after b18 update...)

&lt;size=24&gt;Notes&lt;/size&gt;
How do I progress? Here is a mini-guide:
- First, research the genetic engineering tech.
- Build a Pulper or a Recycler to get organic pulp from wood or corpses (the Recycler needs a Pulper first, though), and a Genetic Extraction Table to get DNA from animals and to build empty incubators.
- Kill the animals to extract their genes.
- Build the Gene Pod to mix the genes of different animals, and fill an empty incubator with the mixture.
- The incubator will hatch in a day. Keep it warm! The creature will be born tamed.
- Results are sometimes random! If you mix Bear and Chicken, you might get a Bearchicken or a Chickenbear. Or the experiment can also go wrong...
- Finally, research the Insectoid Genome, Reptilian Genome and the Advanced genetic engineering techs, build the Advanced Gene Pod and experiment with Insectoids, Reptiles and Thrumbos to get the strongest creatures in the game.
- On a different path, you can research humanoid genetic engineering, and develop hybrid implants to modify your colonists. Yeah, you can create a colonist that lays chicken eggs twice a day. It's hilarious and disgusting.
- On yet another different path, you can research animal enrichment, which allow you to create Alpha animals with the alpha serum extraction table and the animal enrichment center.
- Finally, the age drugs tech allows you to mature your animals much faster!

&lt;size=24&gt;Plans for the future&lt;/size&gt;
- Armoured and Plant-like creatures
- Hybrids with creatures from other animal mods
- Weird special abilities for the existing creatures

&lt;size=24&gt;Compatibility&lt;/size&gt;
Made compatible with A Dog Said using the auto patcher: http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=944381237 (not updated to b18 yet, I think!)
Should be savegame compatible and not break anything. Should!

&lt;size=24&gt;Changelog&lt;/size&gt;
v2.1: Added rodent hybrids. 6 new creatures that breed very fast! (20/11/17)
v2.0: Updated for Beta 18. Added possible compatibility with other mods by adding prefixes to defnames (18/11/17)
v1.601: Modified Age Pills to be slower to craft, made Thrumbochickens pack beasts, and fixed a typo(28/9/17)
v1.6: Added more Alpha Animals (hare, iguana, pig, rat and tortoise) and their animal products. (26/9/17)
v1.48: Added Alpha Animals (first batch of 9, more to come). Added age drugs. Added recycler. Made taming unnecessary for all incubators. (15/9/17)
v1.35: Added A LOT of animal byproducts, and general balancing changes. Most hybrids should be useful in some way now (6/9/17)
v1.3: Added reptile hybrids and squashed many many bugs (25/8/17)
v1.2: Added hybrid humanoid / animal implants (21/8/17)
v1.1: Added the whole Insectoid hybrid family, with new tech. Added skill requirements and electricity requirements (20/8/17)
v1.01: Compatibility with A Dog Said (18/8/17)
v1.0: Release (17/8/17)


		</description>
</ModMetaData>
